# SRIRAM KARTHIK AKELLA

Edmonton, Canada T5J ◆ 825-461-4747 ◆ sk.akella7@gmail.com

## Portfolio Site

• http://www.skarthik.me/

# EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science: Computing Science, Expected in 2024

**University of Alberta** - Edmonton

Member of Undergraduate Association of Computing Science, 2021 to 2023

**Certification**: Algorithms **Stanford University - Remote** 

Studied the fundamental principles of algorithm design.

### Professional Summary

I am currently enrolled in the Science Internship Program (co-op) at my university, which allows me to work full-time for 4, 8, 12 or 16 months. My main interest lies in the field of Software Development and I am looking forward to getting this experience in my next co-op term. I believe that I have the ability to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team. I am confident that my passion for technology and my commitment to excellence make me an ideal candidate for the roles that I am applying for.

### SKILLS

- Python, C, Java
- Database Management
- Test Automation

- API Design
- App Development
- Algorithms

# - Work History

### Network Automation Developer Student, 01/2023 - Current City of Edmonton

- I am currently doing a co-op term at the City of Edmonton's Network Enterprise Team.
- My main role in the team is to develop scripts using Python to automate networking operations, and work with manipulating network data files.
- I also assist the team in analyzing network requirements and configuring computer hardware and software for optimal network communication.

### **Undergraduate Teaching Assistant**, 01/2022 - 06/2022

# **University of Alberta Edmonton**

- TAing CMPUT 175 Introduction to the Foundations of Computation II
- Conducted lab sessions every week and assisted students in one on one and small group setting
- Assisted teaching staff in designing the course.

### **Information Technology Intern**, 07/2019 - 08/2019

### **Kuwait Oil Company Al Ahmadi**

- I have worked as an IT Intern at Kuwait Oil Company receiving practical knowledge on Database and
- Hardware, Cloud Computing, ITIL and ISO Standards, Operating Systems & Computer Networks
- For a term of one week, I had also assisted at the Service Desk of the IT Department of Diyar United Company to help clients by troubleshooting their IT-related issues.

### ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Qify Virtual Clinic KFAS Virtual Hackathon -Created a 'virtual clinic' mobile application for Android and iOS (using Flutter and Firebase) for our participation in the KFAS & CODED Virtual Hackathon -Emergency Resilience The main goal of the project was to eliminate the pressure created on medical systems during the COVID-19 pandemic by creating digital queues for consulting the doctor
- The Smart Eye Developed a device for the visually impaired people called 'The Smart Eye' which can reduce their dependence on others in terms of mobility The device uses Machine Learning & Artificial Intelligence to detect and recognize objects in the field of view of the user.